M. L. Parrish Collection of Victorian Novelists, 1806-1958 (bulk 1830s-1930s ): Finding Aid C0171
Manuscripts Division
- Series 2: Author Files, 1734-1975; 37 boxes
  - Ainsworth, William Harrison, 1805-1882, 1821-1881; 3 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, 1835-1872; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Also included is a heavily-corrected autograph draft of the poem "Yusef and Zorayda," originally composed in November 1835, although the poem was not published for another twenty years, when it appeared in his Ballads: romantic, fantastical and humorous (London, Routledge, 1855). The text in the final published version differs considerably from the text here.
    - Miscellaneous Documents, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Manuscript of Beatrice Tyldesley, or The Lancashire Plot of 1694, an Historical Tale (1), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Manuscript of Beatrice Tyldesley (2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Manuscript of Beatrice Tyldesley (3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Manuscript of Beatrice Tyldesley (4), Additional Leaves, undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Manuscript of Beau Nash, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Manuscript of Chetwynd Calverley, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript of Crichton, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript of The Fall of Somerset, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Galley Proof of St. James's, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Charles Kent, 1861-1879; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Letters to John Partington Aston (1802-1882), 1824 October-1827 November 5; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 5)
      AM 2016-68
      Consists of 4 letters Ainsworth sent from London to his old school friend and literary collaborator, John P. Aston, a lawyer in the Ainsworth family firm, which were composed at a time when Ainsworth was finding his feet as a writer and a publisher. He writes of literary projects and collaborations with which he's engaged, including a collection of short stories and sketches that was to be published by Hurst and Robinson (it never was) that he describes in detail in a letter over twenty pages in length. In the letters, Ainsworth also insists that Aston continue to try to publish despite some setbacks.
  - Anderson, Wellwood, undated; 1 box
    - Lines suggested on reading Mr. J. M. Barrie's first book entitled Better Dead, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Barham, Richard Harris, 1788-1845; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Barnum, Phineas Taylor, 1810-1891; 1 box
    - ALS to W. M. Thackeray and his reply, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Barrie, Sir James Matthew, Bart, 1860-1937; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Letters to Mrs. Thomas Hardy: 1-20, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Letters to Mrs. Thomas Hardy: 21-40, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Letters to Mrs. Thomas Hardy: 41-60, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Letters to Mrs. Thomas Hardy: 61-80, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Letters to Mrs. Thomas Hardy: 81-100, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Letters to Mrs. Thomas Hardy: 101-120, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Letters to Mrs. Thomas Hardy: 121-124, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Barrie, Sir James Matthew, Bart, 1860-1937; 1 box
    - Letters to James B. Pinker, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Half an Hour (last page of the manuscript of Barrie's one act play), undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Account for royalties of Two of Them, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Beatty-Kingston, William, 1837-1900; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Benson, Arthur Christopher, 1862-1925; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 4a)
  - Bentley, Richard, 1794-1871; 1 box
    - Letters addressed to Bentley, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Black, William, 1841-1898; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (3 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Letters to Sir Walter Besant, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Letters to Edward Bradbury, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Letters to Mr. and Mrs. George Boughton and Flossie, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Letters to James R. Osgood, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Letters to John Pettie, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Letters to Sir Edward Russell, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Letters addressed to Black, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Autograph manuscript, signed: "A Day's Stalking", undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Autograph manuscript, signed: "The Heaven of Sad Lovers", undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Blackwood, John, dates not examined; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Bosanquet, Eustace Fulcrand, 1871, undated; 1 box
    - Letters to Falconer Madan, etc., undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Bray, Caroline Hennell, 1814-1905; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Brontë, Charlotte, 1816-1855; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 9 ALsS, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Brontë, Emily Jane, 1818-1848; 1 box
    - Mimeographed film script of Wuthering Heights (Samuel Goldwyn, Inc.), 1938 November 28; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Brontë, Patrick, 1777-1861; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Browne, Hablot Knight, 1815-1882; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Bryant, Arthur Alexis, 1898; 1 box
    - Manuscript of a libretto based on Alice in Wonderland, performed in Cambridge, Mass, 1898; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Caverley, Charles Stuart, 1831-1884; 1 box
    - 2 ALsS concerning C. L. Dodgson, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Carter, John, 1905-1975; 1 box
    - "Victorian Ladies" (review of Parrish's Victorian Lady Novelists book), undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - [Clarke, Joseph Clayton], undated; 1 box
    - Original watercolor drawing of "Trotty Veck" (Dickens' character) by Kyd, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Clough, Arthur Hugh, 1819-1861; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Collins, Harriet (Geddes), undated; 1 box
    - Letters to William Holman Hunt, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Collins, Wilkie, 1824-1889; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1), undated and 1846-1869, 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2), 1870-1879; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (3), 1880-1889; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Letters to members of the Bartley family, with other pieces relating to Collins, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Letters to Francis Carr Beard, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Letters to Richard Bentley, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Letters to Andrew Chatto, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Letters to Richard Henry Dana, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Letters to Robert du Pontavice de Heussey, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Collins, Wilkie, 1824-1889; 2 boxes
    - Letters to Albéric Iserbyt, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Harper & Brothers, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Hunter, Rose & Co., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Charles Kent, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Letters, etc., to Frederick Lehmann and members of the Lehmann family, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Mrs. Mitchell, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Anne B. S. Proctor, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Letters to William A. Seaver, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Letters to William Winter, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Letters addressed to Wilkie Collins, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous autograph material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Contract between Wilkie Collins and Charles Lahure, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - The last will and testament (photocopy), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Ms. in French: Armadale, Acte 3, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - The Moonstone: notes and related material, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Poor Miss Finch, AMs, undated; 2 boxes
      - 1st weekly part: dedication and leaves 1-15, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - 2nd weekly part: leaves 16-29, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - 3rd weekly part: leaves 30-41, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - 4th weekly part: leaves 42-55, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - 5th weekly part: leaves 56-67, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - 6th weekly part: leaves 68-78, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - 7th weekly part: leaves 79-89, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - 8th weekly part: leaves 90-101, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - 9th weekly part: leaves 102-112, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - 10th weekly part: leaves 113-122, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - 11th weekly part: leaves 123-132, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - 12th weekly part: leaves 133-143, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - 13th weekly part: leaves 144-154, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - 14th weekly part: leaves 155-164, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - 15th weekly part: leaves 165-176, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - 16th weekly part: leaves 177-187, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - 17th weekly part: leaves 188-198, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - 18th weekly part: leaves 199-209, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - 19th weekly part: leaves 210-221, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - 20th weekly part: leaves 222-233, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - 21st weekly part: leaves 234-245, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - 22nd weekly part: leaves 246-256, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - 23rd weekly part: leaves 257-268, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - 24th weekly part: leaves 269-280, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - 25th weekly part: leaves 281-291, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - 26th weekly part: leaves 292-307 (end), undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - Quill Pen, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 20A)
  - Colvin, Sir Sidney, 1845-1927; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Cope, Sir William Henry, Bart, 1811-1892; 1 box
    - Letters to Sir William, Sir Anthony and Alice Cope, from Rose, Mary and Maurice Kingsley, and others, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - The Cornhill Magazine, undated; 1 box
    - "To Correspondents" (published poem), undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Craik, Dinah Maria Mulock, 1826-1887; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Letters to William Isbister, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - "At a Tabernacle" (AM20870), undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - "Meadowside House", undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - "Work for Idle Hands", undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Craik, George Lillie, 1798-1866; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Craik, Georgiana M. (Georgiana Marion), 1831-1895, undated; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 box
      - AN by Alfred Lord Tennyson (in third person and in hand of Emily Tennyson), undated; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Craik, James, 1802-1870; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Crane, Walter, 1845-1915; 1 box
    - Pen-and-ink drawing for Farina, by George Meredith, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Cross, John Walter, 1840-1924; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Dalling and Bulwer, William Henry Lytton Earle Bulwer, baron, 1801-1872, undated; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Davray, Henry D., 1873, undated; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 1a)
  - De la Ramée, Louise (Ouida), 1839-1908; 2 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Alice Danyell and members of her family, with related material (1 of 2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Alice Danyell and members of her family, with related material (2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Additional letters to Alice Danyell and members of her family, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Letter to George Williamson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - De la Ramée, Louise (Ouida), 1839-1908; 2 boxes
    - Letters to Herbert Danyell, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Isadore de Lara, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Letters to J. Anderson Rose, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Charles Marriott, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Letters to H. S. Salt, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 4A)
    - Letters to T. Fischer Unwin, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Lady Anna Chandos Pole, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Florence: 1321-1889", undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Princess Napraxine (1 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Princess Napraxine (2 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Princess Napraxine (3 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Dickens, Catherine Thomson Hogarth, 1815-1879; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Letters to Peter Cunningham, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Letters to Thomas Mitton, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - ALS to George Reynolds, Octr. 13th [1841?], 1 p., undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Dickens, Charles, 1837-1896 (son), 1891-1893; 2 boxes
    - Dickens, Charles, 1837-1896 (Son), Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Dickens, Charles, 1837-1896 (Son), Letters to The Lecture Agency, Ltd., 1891-1893; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 6)
      Letters relate to North American lecture tours; one letter is addressed specifically to Gerald Christy, the company's managing director.
      AM 2017-159
      Purchase, 2017
  - Dickens, Mary, 1838-1896; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - D'Israeli, Isaac, 1766-1848; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Disraeli, Benjamin, 1st Earl of Beaconsfield, 1804-1881; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," Decr. 21, 1831 from Bradenham House, [2] pp., undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Alroy, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Disraeli, Mary Ann Evans, Viscountess of Beaconsfield, 1792-1872; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge, 1832-1898 (Lewis Carroll), 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Letters to members of the Hatch family, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Letter with enclosure to Mary Louis Jackson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence with J. and E. Kish, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Letters to E. Gertrude Thomson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Letters to James Welton, undated; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Letters addressed to Dodgson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Acrostic to Alice Crompton, AMs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge, 1832-1898 (Lewis Carroll), undated; 1 box
    - "Alice in Wonderland: The Christmas Gift of Lewis Carroll," television script, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "A Logical Paradox," Ms., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - A Selection from the Letters of Lewis Carroll, typescript (1 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - A Selection from the Letters of Lewis Carroll, typescript (2 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - A Selection from the Letters of Lewis Carroll, typescript (3 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Through the Looking-glass (Y. R. Chao's translation into Chinese), positive photostat of corrected page proof, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "What the Tortoise said to Achilles," Ms., undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Dodgson, Frances Menella, 1877-1963; 1 box
    - Letters to Falconer Madan, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Du Maurier, George Louis Palmella Busson, 1834-1896; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Drawings, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Ebers, John, 1785?-1830?, undated; 1 box
    - ALS to James Storey, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Eliot, George (Marian Cross, née Evans), 1819-1880; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Letters to Elizabeth Rayner Parkes Belloc (1 of 2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Manuscript Notes on the Persecution of the Jews in Spain, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Eliot, George (Marian Cross, née Evans), 1819-1880; 1 box
    - Letters to Elizabeth Rayner Parkes Belloc (2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Account book, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Quarry," AMs in notebook for an unfinished novel, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Faithfull, Emily, 1835-1895; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Ford, Edward Onslow, 1852-1901; 1 box
    - Correspondence ... concerning his marble bust of W. M. Thackeray as a boy, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Forster, John, 1812-1876; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Foss, Hubert James, 1899-1953; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Fuller, Hester Thackeray Ritchie, undated; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Letters to W. J. Williams of Smith, Elder & Co., undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Furman, Dorothy, undated; 1 box
    - Material relating to The (Robert Louis) Stevenson Society, Stephen Chalmers, and 2 ALsS from sculptor Gutzon Borglum, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Furniss, Harry, 1854-1925; 1 box
    - 6 original pen-and-ink drawings for or related to Lewis Carroll's Sylvie and Bruno and Sylvie and Bruno concluded, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Proof, suppressed state, of an illustration for Lewis Carroll's Sylvie and Bruno, p. 96, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 12a)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 12b)
    - Pen-and-ink drawing of Hall Caine, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 12c)
  - Gaskell, Elizabeth Cleghorn Stevenson, 1810-1865; 1 box
    - Letters addressed to Mrs. Gaskell, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (included in Chapple and Pollard edition), undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (not in Chapple and Pollard edition), undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Gaskell, William, 1805-1884; 1 box
    - "Not under the Law, but under Grace," Ms.; letters from various correspondents (including 1 ALS from M. E. Gaskell) to S. Farrington; letters from S. Farrington to Horace [?], undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Gaskell, Margaret Emily, 1837-1913; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Gosse, Sir Edmund William, 1849-1928; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - "Stevenson's 'In the South Seas'," AMS, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Gould, Sir Frances Carruthers, 1844-1925; 1 box
    - "Tea at the Hotel Cecil" pen-and-ink drawing after Tenniel, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Gray, Asa, 1810-1888; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Grenfell, Pascoe, 1761-1838; 1 box
    - Sentiment written for his daughter Fanny's (later Mrs. Charles Kingsley) album, 1831 August 26; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Guild of Literature and Art, London, undated; 1 box
    - Resolutions, AMss, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Hardy, Florence Emily Dugdale, d. 1937, undated; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Letters to Howard Bliss (1 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Hardy, Florence Emily Dugdale, d. 1937, undated; 1 box
    - Letters to Howard Bliss (2 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Howard Bliss: envelopes (3 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 2)